Never give up on family.
The Fate of the Furious is a action, crime,
thriller film directed by F. Gary Gray.
When a mysterious woman seduces Dom into the world of crime and a betrayal of those
closest to him, the crew face trials that will test them as never before.
Dominic Toretto, played by Vin Diesel.
Deckard Shaw, played by Jason Statham.
Luke Hobbs, played by Dwayne Johnson.
Letty Ortiz, played by Michelle Rodriguez.
Roman Pearce, played by Tyrese Gibson.
Tej Parker, played by Ludacris.
The Fate of the Furious is a 2017 American action film directed by F.
Gary Gray and written by Chris Morgan.
It is the sequel to Furious 7 (2015) and the eighth
installment in the Fast & Furious franchise.
The film stars Vin Diesel as Dominic Toretto, alongside Dwayne Johnson, Jason Statham, Michelle Rodriguez, Tyrese Gibson,
Chris "Ludacris" Bridges, Scott Eastwood, Nathalie Emmanuel, Elsa Pataky, Kurt Russell, and Charlize Theron.
In the film, Dom has settled down with his wife Letty Ortiz, until cyberterrorist Cipher (Theron) coerces him
into working for her and turns him against his team, forcing them to find Dom and take down Cipher.
The eighth installment was planned since 2014, and in March 2015 it
was revealed the film would be set in New York City.
Preparations for the film began immediately before the release of
Furious 7, with Diesel, Morgan, and producer Neal H.
Moritz re-signing.
After setting an initial release date in that same month,
casting took place between April and June.
In October, Gray was announced to direct the film in the place of
James Wan, who had directed the previous installment.
Composer Brian Tyler, who had scored the third, fourth, fifth, and
seventh installments, returned to compose the score.
Principal photography began in March 2016 in locations such as Mývatn, Havana, Atlanta, Cleveland,
and New York City, continuing the franchise's tradition of filming around the world.
With an estimated production budget of up to $270 million, it
is one of the most expensive films ever made.
This is the first film in the series since The Fast and the Furious: Tokyo Drift (2006) not
to star Paul Walker as Brian O'Conner, following his death in November 2013.
The Fate of the Furious premiered in Berlin on April 4, 2017, and was theatrically
released in the United States on April 14, by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for the performances of
the cast and action sequences but criticism for the storyline.
The film was a box office success, grossing over $1.2 billion worldwide, making it the thirtieth film (and the second in the franchise, after Furious
7) to gross over $1 billion, the third-highest-grossing film of 2017, and the eleventh highest-grossing film of all time at the time.
It also grossed $541.9 million worldwide during its opening weekend, which made it the highest-grossing
worldwide opening of all time until the release of Avengers: Infinity War a year later.
The film was followed by a spin-off, Hobbs & Shaw
(2019), and a direct sequel, F9 (2021).
The film explores themes of new york city, submarine,
rescue mission, sequel, street race.
The tone is intense.